GARY JOEL WHITE

Hi, I'm Gary, a Front-End developer with over 4 years of experience, including 1 year specialising in TypeScript and React. Originally from the UK and currently based in Leipzig, I'm very willing to relocate for the right job. Find out more about me and my work.

Front-End Developer Leipzig, Germany +49 159 0148 1213 gary909@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

FRONT-END DEVELOPER (DEC 2023 - NOW)

MacroSolutions GmbH, Leipzig, DE

Responsible for maintaining, improving and developing new features into the frontend of our intra-logistics warehouse software with a strong focus on UX|UI. Successfully completed several key projects, including:

• Development from concept to code with testing using agile methodologies

• Set up API communication with the backend to retrieve stock from automated guided vehicles • Implemented User Authentication and Permission Management with secure login and session management • Pagination: Enhanced the handling of large datasets and increased performance of warehouse results data • Conducted Code Reviews

FRONT-END DEVELOPER (AUG 2019 - AUG 2023)

Lodgit Hotelsoftware GmbH, Leipzig, DE

In charge of maintaining, updating and implementing new features for the company website utilising Contao CMS (HTML, CSS, Javascript).

• Created custom websites and booking pages for clients • Developed mock-ups for new software implementations • Monitored and optimised system performance • Tracked & improved SEO performance using SEMrush, Screaming Frog and Google Search Console • Ensured legal GDPR compliance across company websites • Collaborated with cross-functional teams and stakeholders

TRANSMISSION CONTROLLER (2002 - 2019)

Argiva/Phantasia/Frame 25 Recruitment, Oxfordshire, UK

Responsible for managing and overseeing broadcast output for multiple digital TV channels for a variety of clients such as ESPN, BBC Poland, Disney, Channel 5, Sony and Technicolor. Monitoring of Live broadcast, pre-recorded content, commercials and video feeds. Handling technical faults.

OPERATIONS ASSISTANT (2001 - 2002)

British Forces Broadcasting Services, Gerrards Cross, UK Assistance, Audio engineering, digital editing and maintaining equipment.

EDUCATION

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP (MARCH - MAY 2019)

Ironhack, Berlin, 9 week Bootcamp

Web Dev bootcamp covering the fundamentals of HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, TypeScript, Express, MongoDB, testing & agile methodologies.

ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING (2013 - 2014)

International Correspondence Schools, Bachelor of Technology (BTEC)

Electricity & Circuit Theory, Inductance, Capacitance & Solid State Devices, Electronic Applications, Analog & Digital Circuits.

SOUND ENGINEERING WITH MUSIC TECHNOLOGY (1999 - 2001)

Amersham & Wycombe College, BTEC + Higher National Diploma

Acoustics, Music Technology, Sound Design, Recording & Media Business.

LINKS

Personal Website Blog GitHub LinkedIn

HARD SKILLS

Webdev: HTML, CSS, Javascript/TypeScript, React, Git, SEO, Contao CMS, Unit testing (Jest), Adobe Photoshop/ Illustrator Hardware: C++, Arduino, KiCAD, Analog/Digital Electronics VR: C#, Unity, Visual Studio, Blender

CERTIFICATES

XR Terra: 4 week VR developer course (Unity).

Udemy: The Complete Web Dev Bootcamp (65 hour online course).

Udacity: Android Development, scholarship funded by google.

HOBBIES

DIY Synthesizers (combining hardware & software). VR game/app creation using Unity. Pizza making (and eating). Vespa repair (ongoing).

